Newland/Zeuner Collection
Music Division, Library of Congress
- Music of Charles Zeuner (Box 48-57)
  - Secular vocal music (Box 55, Box 57)
    - Zeuner as Composer: Manuscript copies in other hands (Box 55)
      - A Parting song (Box 55)
    - Zeuner as Composer: Printed music (Box 55)
      - Blow, blow, blow, thou winter wind (Box 55)
      - If thou hast crush'd a flow'r (Box 55)
      - Take, oh take those lips away (Box 55)
      - When that I was a little tiny boy (Box 55)
    - Zeuner as Arranger: Printed music (Box 55)
      - Break my heart! Break my heart! (Box 55)
      - The Evening gun (Box 55)
      - The Sailor's grave (Box 55)
      - Wandering by the moonlight shore (Box 55)
    - Zeuner as Copyist (Box 55, Box 57)
      - The African's Complaint (Box 55)
      - Bengalee Hymn (Box 57)
  - Instruction and study materials (Box 56)
    - [10 books of figured bass exercises] (Box 56)
    - [Miscellaneous cover pages, fragments and scraps] (Box 56)
Music of the Newland/Zeuner Collection
Title only
16 • [Printed fragments for piano and violin] No. 8. (Op. 53. No. 2.)
42 • Advice to the Fair. Sung by Mrs. Wrighten at Vauxhall. Set by Mr. Hook.
12 • Agamemnon, Ballet pour le Clavecin.
45 • Apollo Sammlung auserlesener Gesangstücke aus Opern, Concerten, Oratorien, etc., alter und neuer Zeit.
40 • As the Hart Panteth
12 • Blumen aus 100 Opern eine Ausgewählte Sammlung gefälliger und beliebter Opern Melodien im leichtesten auszuge für's Piano-Forte. Zur Unterhaltung und Aufmunterung für junge Piano-Forte-Spieler zweckmässig eingerichtet von G. W. Marks.
16 • Budget of Blunders
45 • Cruel Flatterer - The admired Duet Sung by Miss Abrahams and Miss Field in the Critic. Adapted for the Harpsichord, with English & Italian Words.
42 • Dänische [und] Schwedische Nationallieder aus der Sammlung, die gegen 90 Melodien enthält. (Beylage zur allgemeinen musikalischen Zeitung. No. 6, 7).
17 • Ecossaise für die Aura (et al.). Beilage zur allgemeinen musikal. Zeitung, No. 30; No. 5.
47 • Elementary Principles of Music
10 • Fantaisie and Nocturne
21 • Fantasie
47 • General=Bass. Exemel. in C clef and F clef
47 • Generalbass.
6 • Grand Capriccios for Organ
23 • Hail Columbia [et al]
39 • Handel & Haydn Collection.
46 • Hunters Glee
23 • Introduction - Maestoso Adagio
12 • La Cachucha - The Celebrated Castanet Spanish Dance, as Danced by Melle Fanny Elssler. Arranged for the Piano Forte.
16 • Ladies Hornpipe
42 • Lied eines betrübten Mädchens an die Tugend [and] Alles, nur nicht die Ruhe [and] Ist sie von Adel? No. 6-8.
42 • Lieder der Schweizerischen Musikgesellschaft bey Ihrer 17n Versammlung in Zürich. 1829.
4 • Litanies Hymns Vespers Chant Mass.
31 • Magnificat - Canticum B. V. M.
40 • Mary Our Lovely Queen of May
29 • Mass No. 3
4 • Mass. Kyrie and Gloria. Dies irae. Dona eis. Requiem
24 • Missa de Angelis
9 • Musikalische Unterhaltungen. Erstes Quartal, von Neujahr bis Ostern 1775. [No. 18]
9 • My Aine Kind Dearie, a favorite Scotish Air, arranged with Variations for the Piano Forte.
21 • Nel cor più - Solo for Clarinet in B-flat with Orchestra
9 • No me mires asi! Habanera para piano por E. Z.
40 • O my Redeemer
46 • Oh! Then We Live!
10 • Overture aus der ?? Eigesinnige
4 • Overtures. Piano solo. Violin.
16 • Polonaise pour le Violon
13 • Primo
42 • Rosline Castle.
10 • Sammlung Neuer Tänze
24 • Sanctus
29 • Sanctus
42 • Spring the Soul Firing. A favorite Song in the Spanish Barber. No. 26.
46 • The African's Complaint
10 • The Blessings of Peace
38 • The Boston Handel and Haydn Society Collection of Sacred Music. Vol. II
38 • The Boston Handel and Haydn Society Collection of Sacred Music. Vol. IV
42 • The Braes of Yarrow. Sung by Miss Thornton.
39 • The Choral Harmonist. Vol. 3, No. 25-32.
42 • The Larks Shrill Notes. Sung by Mrs. Vincent at Vauxhall.
42 • The Soger Lassie. Sung by Miss Thornton.
42 • The Wandering Sailor. Sung by Mr. Bannister in the Summer Amusement.
56 • Trauerlied auf Ludwig den sechszehnten. Verfasst und in Musik gesetzt von Roman Schad.
45 • Vous l'ordonnez - To be Sung either as an Air, Duett or Trio [by Monsigny?].
30 • W. A. Newland's collection of Sacred Music, Nos. 1-10.
30 • W. A. Newland's collection of Vespers.
40 • We praise thee O God / Te Deum
46 • When music swells
9 • XXIV Pièces pour le Piano-Forté à l'usage des Commencans. Oeuv: 1
By Composer
Adam, Adolphe
38 • Noël [with] Orgue Mélodium par A. Adam.
Adam, Adolphe and Ludwig Wenzel Lachnith
7 • Premières Leçons et 38 Pièces agréables Handstücke de tout genre par gradation, le tout doigté, pour le Pianoforte à l'usage des Élèvesdu Conservatoire de Musique, par Adam & Lachnith
Albrechtsberger, Johann Georg
5 • Organ Fugue
André, Anton
31 • Te Deum Laudamus komponirt und in einen Klavier-Auszug gebracht von Anton André. 60stes Werk.
André (arranger)
32 • Jesu Mater
Araciel, Diego de
18 • Tre Terzetti per Serenata a Violino, Viola e Chitarra composti da Diego de Araciel.
Arne, Thomas Augustine
41 • (The wanton God who pierces hearts... ) Sung by Mrs. Clive.
Auber, Daniel-François-Esprit
11 • La Neige. Opera en quatre actes composé par D. F. E. Auber arrangé avec accompagnement de Piano-Forté No. 103.
11 • Ouverturen für das Piano-forte solo. Nro. 2. Gustav, oder der Maskenball v. D. F. E. Auber.
Aulagnier, Antonin
23 • Quadrille Deuriante par Aulagnier.
Baij, Tomasso
33 • Miserere
Batiste, Edouard
5 • The Great Organ: a selection of pieces performed at the Inauguration [Nov. 2, 1863] of the Great Organ (Boston Music Hall) and at subsequent concerts
Battmann, J. L.
24 • Mass in F
Beczwarzowsky, Antonin F.
18 • III Sonates pour le Piano Forte avec Violon et Violoncelle obligés, par A. Beczwarzowsky. Oeuvre 3me.
Beethoven, Ludwig van
18 • [String Quartets], Op. 18, No. 1-3
10 • [Unidentified]
20 • Adelaide von Beethoven. Zur gewöhnlichen Clavier Begleitung gesetzt von J. P. Heuschkel.
23 • Concerto [Op. 15]
41 • Gesänge mit Begleitung des Klaviers in Musikgesetzt von L. van Beethoven.No. 16. [Op. 52, no. 5]
42 • Knowest thou the land [Op. 75, no.1]
24 • Kyrie from Op. 27
7 • LIme [51st] Sonate pour le Pianoforte composée par Louis van Beethoven. Op. 54
24 • Mass in C
41 • May Gesang.Wieherrlich Leuchtet mir die Natur von Göthe[and] Ohne Liebe Lebe, wer da Kann Gedicht von Lessing,in Musik gesezt mit Clavier Begleitung von L. van Beethoven.No. 11 u. 12.
• Mount of Olives; Alleluja Chorus. => see: Haydn, Mass in C, No. 2, Box 26
11 • Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 4,5,6]
13 • Polonoise Concertante à quatre mains pour le Pianoforte par Louis van Beethoven. Tiré de l'Oeuvre 56.
7 • Rondo pour le Clavecin ou Piano Forte par Louis van Beethoven. [Op. 51]
41 • Scena ed Aria, Ha! Treuloser Meineidgerverräthrischer Barbar? =(Ah! perfido, spergiuro barbaro traditor)in Musik gesezt mit Clavier Begleitung von L. van Beethoven. No. 13.
7 • Sieben Ländlerische Tänze für's Piano-Forte von L. v. Beethoven
23 • Sonata [Op. 17] [Flauto o Violino, Corno in F]
16 • Sonata in F., op. 17
14 • Sonata per il Piano-forte ed un Violino obligato, scritta in uno stile molto concertante, quasi come d'un concerto. Composta per L. van Beethoven. Opera 47. [Kreutzer]
14 • Sonate für Piano-Forte und Violin von Ludwig van Beethoven. 96tes Werk.
14 • Sonate pour le Forte-Piano avec un Cor, oû Violoncelle composée par Louis van Beethoven. Oeuvre 17.
11 • Symphonien für das Pianoforte zu zwei Händen, arrangirt von Louis Winkler.
14 • Tre Sonate per il Clavicembalo o Forte-Piano con un Violino dal Sigr. Luigi van Beethoven. Opera 12.
11 • Triumph-Marsch aus dem Trauerspiele Tarpeia von Louis von Beethoven.
14 • Trois Sonates pour Piano-Forté, accompagné de Violon, par L. van Beethoven. Oeuvre 12.
Bellini, Vincenzo
21 • [La Sonnambula] Overture.
41 • Beatrice di Tenda. Come t'adoro e quanto, cavatina nella Beatrice di Tenda del maestro Bellini.
22 • La Sonnambula. Overture
41 • La Sonnambula. Ah non credea mirarti. Air Finale per voce di soprano.
22 • Norma. Potpourri
11 • Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 7,8,11,62]
11 • Ouverturen für das Pianoforte. No. 13. Bellini, z. Oper: Die Puritaner.
15 • Potpourri [from] Norma. Arrangée pour deux violons par J. G. Busch. Nouvelle ed.
Beriot, Charles Auguste de and Julius Benedict
15 • Duo Brillant pour Piano et Violon sur les Motifs de l'Opéra de Bellini, La Somnambule par J. Benedict et C. de Beriot.
Beriot, Charles Auguste de and George Alexander Osborne
15 • Duo Brillant pour Piano et Violon sur l'Opéra de Bellini I Puritani par G. A. Osborne et C. de Beriot.
15 • Duo Brillant sur Le Domino Noir par C. de Bériot avec Osborne. Op. 31.
15 • Variations de Concert pour Piano et Violon sur un motif de l'opéra L'Ambassadrice par G. A. Osborne & C. de Beriot.
Beriot, Charles Auguste de and Edward Wolff
15 • Grand Duo sur des motifs de Robert le Diable.
Bertoni, Ferdinando Gioseffo
41 • La Virginella. Adapted as a favorite Lesson for the Harpsichord
Bianchi, Francesco
15 • Ouverture Della Villanella Rapita arrangée pour le Clavecin ou Piano Forté par Mr. Haussman.
Blangini, F.
• [Song]. => see: Paer, Romance, Box 42
Bochsa, (Robert) Nicolas Charles
18 • Grand Duo pour Harpe et Piano avec Acc. d'Orchestre ad libitum par N. Ch. Bochsa.
Bochsa, N. Charles
18 • Neuf Variations pour la harpe
Bohlman
23 • La Sorcière des Ardennes
Boieldieu, Adrien
21 • [Caliphe von Bagdad] Overtura.
22 • Caliphe de Bagdad. Overture
Boieldieu, Adrien (arranger)
14 • Caliphe v[on] Bagdad - Ouverture
Bordese, Luigi
31 • Alma Redemptoris Mater
32 • Ecce panis angelorum
39 • Flowers of Sacred Harmony
32 • Inviolata integra
24 • Mass [in G minor]
24 • Mass [in G minor]; Kyrie
33 • Miserere
• O salutaris hostia. => see: Clifton, Ecce Deus Salvator Meus, Box 32
34 • Stabat Mater
Bordogni, Giulio Marco
41 • 24 nouvelles Vocalises faciles et progressives à la portée de toutes les voix avec piano par Marco Bordogni. Introduction aux 36 Vocalises. Livr. I.
Bornhardt, J. H. C.
41 • Das Musikalische Tempo. Ein Gesang mit Begleitung der Guitarre. Zur Erbauung für jedes Alter. Gedichtet von Haug. Componirt von J. H. C. Bornhardt.
41 • Der Taucher, Ballade von Schiller zur Guitarre componirt von J.H.C. Bornhardt. 65tes Werck.
Brachthuizer, D.
12 • Sonate facile à Quatre Mains pour le Pianoforte par D. Brachthuizer.
Bühler, F.
25 • Benedictus
32 • Magnificat
25 • Mass No. 1 in E-flat
25 • Missa brevis in A, No. 3
25 • Missa brevis in F, No. 2
Calcott, J. W.
36 • These as they change, Almighty Father
Cambini, Giuseppe Maria
18 • Six Quatuors par Cambini. Op. 15.
15 • Trois Grands Duos extraits des Ouvrages de Pleyel arrangés pour deux Violons par Cambini. Livre 1 & 2.
Campana, Fabio
44 • Dimmi che m'ami! Duettino. Musica del M. Campana.
Carr, Benjamin
39 • Anthem for Christmas
39 • Jubilate Deo (O be joyful)
56 • Jubilate Deo (with a Gloria by Charles Zeuner)
• Mass; Sanctus, Agnus Dei. => see: Lederer, Mass in D, Box 26
34 • Te Deum
Castegnier, A.
24 • Agnus Dei par Mr. A. Castegnier.
Castelli
• [Song]. => see: Paer, Romance, Box 42
Cherubini, Luigi
• Ave Maria. => see: Haydn, Mass in B-flat, Box 26
35 • O Salutaris
• O salutaris hostia. => see: Haydn, Mass in B-flat, Box 26
45 • Opening Round.
Cimarosa, Domenico
22 • Il Matrimonio. Overture
25 • Kyrie
21 • Matrimonio Segreto. Ouverture.
Clapisson, Louis
44 • Le Coffret de St. Domingue. Opéra comique en un acte. Paroles de Mr Emile Deschamps.
Clasing, I. H.
38 • Canon aus dem Oratorium: Belsazar.In Musik gesetzt von I. H. Clasing.(Beilage zur allgem. musickalischen Zeitung 1825. No. 52; No. VI).
Clementi, Muzio
7 • Deux Sonates pour le Forte Piano composées par Muzio Clementi. Oeuvre 34. Nouvelle Editione, et corrigées par l'auteur
1 • Oeuvres Complettes de Muzio Clementi. Cahier I, VI.
7 • Tre Sonate Per Clavicembalo o Forte-Piano Composte dal Sig. Muzio Clementi. Opera [23]
18 • Tre sonate per il Clavicembalo o Forte Piano con l'accompagnamento d'un Violino e Basso composte dal Sig. Muzio Clementi. Opera 23.
Clifton, Arthur
47 • Clifton's Piano-forte Preceptor, containing the Rudiments of Music, Exercises & Rules for Fingering and the Major & Minor Scales, together with a selection of Popular Airs & Lessons, Adapted by the Author. Third Edition.
Clifton, J. C.
32 • Ecce Deus Salvator Meus
Concone, Joseph
24 • Concone's Mass in F. Composed for 2 voices by J. Concone. Arranged for 4 voices by A. Andrews. [Kyrie]
25 • Mass [in F]
Corelli, Arcangelo
15 • Sonate a Violino e Violono o Cimbalo da Arcangelo Corelle da Fusignano Opera Quinta Parte Prima.
Cornopean
35 • Gloria
Costa, M.
32 • Date sonitum pastores
Cramer, J. B. (Johann Baptist)
7 • Collection des Sonates brillantes pour le Piano Forte. Nro. [1] Composées par J.B. Cramer.
7 • Three Sonatas for the Piano-Forte by J. B. Cramer. Op. 23
Cramer, Johann Baptist (arranger)
11 • Lord MacDonald's Reel, Arranged as a Rondo for the Piano-Forte by J.B. Cramer
Crotch, William
36 • Palestine; Recitative and aria
Cunnington, W. P.
39 • 3 Dirges - Sung at the Solemn Requiem at St. Joseph's Church on March 18, 1863
Czerny, Carl
12 • Les Trois Soeurs. Rondinos pour le Piano à 6 mains. Op. 609, No. 5 - Air Suisse par Ch. Czerny.
12 • Practische Takt-Schule. 44 leichte Uebungsstücke für das Pianoforte zu 4 Händen in fortschreitender Ordnung für Anfänger und vorgerückte Schüler von Carl Czerny 824stes Werk. Heft 2.
7 • Quatrième Rondino pour le Pianoforte seul sur un motif favori de Mr. Fesca composé par Charles Czerny. Op. 39
Daunas, Pedro
25 • Missa Espagnole
25 • Missa Pastorelle pour la Nuit de Noël
Della Maria, Pierre-Antoine-Dominique
11 • L'Opera comique. [Potpourri].
41 • Le Prisonnier Aria aus der Oper le Prisonier. Wenn ich in jenen finstern Mauern.
11 • Ouverture Du Prisonnier ou La Ressemblance. Musique du Cn. Dellamaria arrangée pour le Piano par L'Auteur
41 • Romance. No. 18. Le Prisonnier ou la Ressemblance. Paroles du Duval, Musique du Delamaria.
Desvignes, P.
30 • Pie Jesu
Devienne, François
17 • Six trios pour deux flutes
Diabelli, Anton
17 • Divertissements d'après des Themes de Rossini, Caraffa etc. pour Flute et Pianoforte composés par A. Diabelli. Liv. 1.
7 • Euterpe, eine Reihe moderner und vorzüglich beliebter Tonstücke zur Erheiterung in Stunden der Musse für das Piano-Forte herausgegeben von Anton Diabelli. No. 220. No. [55,93,95]
Dibdin, Charles
41 • Brother Jack, written & composed by Mr. Dibdin, and sung by him in his new entertainment called the Cake House.
41 • The Miller's Wedding Day. Composed by Mr. C. Dibdin.
Diehlman
34 • Sub tuum
Dielman, H.
25 • Mass [in C]; Kyrie Eleison [in C]
25 • Mass for Two Tenors & Bass [in F]; Kyrie, Gloria
Dietsch, Pierre-Louis-Philippe
25 • Mass in B-flat
44 • Mois de Marie. 20 Motets à une, deux et trois Voix égales avec Acc. d'Orgue ou d'Harmonium ou de Piano par L. Dietsch.
Dittersdorf, Karl
44 • Aus dem rothen Käppchen
Donizetti, Gaetano
• Ave maris stella. => see: Haydn, Mass in B-flat, Box 26
22 • La Fille du Regiment. Overture
• March from La Favorita. => see: Fry, Fill Up, Fill Up
11 • Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 45,47,48,49,63,64]
35 • Vexilla regis
Dos Santos, A. F.
25 • Mass in G for 3 voices
Dreyer, J. M.
34 • Stella coeli
Dussek, Johann Ladislaus
7 • Thême Varié Pour Le Forte-Piano compossé por J. L. Dussek
Emerick, Albert G.
38 • Sacred Sentences from the Bible,Designed as introductory piecesfor public worship, Selected and Composed,with an accompaniment for the organ by Albert G. Emerick.Book II.
Emmerig, W. J.
25 • Missa Solemnis in D. Organ accompaniment by W. A. Newland
Est, L. B.
32 • Beata es virgo
Este
30 • [Unidentified]
Fairlamb, J. R.
• Wedding March. => see: Mozart, Mass No. 12, Box 28
Farmer, Henry
25 • Mass in B-flat
Feltz, L.
26 • Mass in E-flat
Fesca, Friedrich Ernst
18 • Quartetto. Op. 38
Field, John
7 • Rondeau Favori pour Piano-Forté composé par John Field. No. 2.
Fisher, John Abraham
41 • The Morning Invitation, a Cantata by A. Fisher.
Flotow, Friedrich von
22 • [Alessandro] Stradella. Overture
Ford, J.
41 • The Resolution. Set by Mr. J. Ford.
Franzl, Ferdinand
12 • Adolph and Clara op. 18 - Overture
56 • Adolph and Clara. Overture
22 • Adolphe & Clara. Overture
15 • Concerto pour deux violons par Ferdinand Franzl. Oeuvre 4me.
Freystädtler, Franz Jacob
7 • 10 Variazionen über das alte wohlbekante Preussische Lied: Schwerin bist wirklich todt? für das Pianoforte von Freystädtler
Fry, William Henry
23 • Fill Up, Fill Up
22 • Leonora
Fuss, Johann
31 • Hymnus. Johann Fuss in Wien. (Beylage zur allgemeinen musikalischen Zeitung, [No. 51]; No. 9).
Gebauer, François René
17 • Six duos pour deux flutes
Gelinek, Joseph
7 • Rondeau ou Polonoise favorite pour le Piano Forté, par Gelinek.
7 • Sonatina leicht und angenehm für das Piano-Forte von Herrn Abbé Gelinek. No. [2]
7 • Variationen über die Cavatine in Rossini's Tancred, für das Pianoforte von Abbé Gelinek. No. 96
7 • Variations pour le Pianoforte composées par L'Abbé Gelinek. No. [8,93,100]
Gelsin, M. A.
35 • Venite Adoremus
Generalis
26 • Mass in G
Giorza, Paolo
33 • Regina coeli
Glück, Carl
7 • Twenne Walsar och en Cotillon componerade och arrangerade för Piano-Forte af Carl Glück
Gluck, Christoph Willibald
56 • Iphigénie en Aulide=Iphigenia in Aulis, Tragédie lyrique en trois actes=Lyrische Tragödie in drie Aufzügen, Mise en musique par Mr. le chevalier Gluck=In Musik gesetzt von dem Ritter Gluck. Arrangée pour le Pianoforte von J. D. Sander. Erster Act.
11 • Ouverturen für das Piano-Forte solo. [Nro. 50,51]
Gounod, Charles
26 • 2d Messe à 4 voci per tenori e bassi
26 • [Unidentified]
31 • Ave Maria by Charles Gounod.
24 • Gounod's Messe Solennelle (St. Cecilia) with Latin and English words, Edited, and the English words adapted, by W. H. Birch.
26 • Messe Solennelle (St. Cecilia)
Graffula, Claudio S.
23 • Col. Duryee's Quick Step [et al]
23 • Oh would I were a boy again
Greene, Maurice
39 • Duet - The Lord is my shepherd
Greith, Carl
24 • Responsoria ad Missam. In tono Solemni ad Voces aequales. (From the official Ratisbon edition.) Arranged and Harmonized by Carl Greith.
Grétry, André Ernest Modeste
15 • Ouverture et quatre Airs de Danse de Panurge de Gretry. Arrangés pour Clavecin ou Forte-Piano avec Accompagnement de Violon par Hulmandel. No. 573.
Guglielmi, Pietro
32 • Gratias agimus tibi
Gulielmus
35 • Gratias agimus tibi
Gyrowetz, Adalbert
20 • Sinfonie Periodique Divers Instrumens composée par Mr. Adalberto Gyrowetz.
Hachs, T. von
26 • Missa pro pace
Handel, George Frideric
36 • Angels ever bright and fair - Larghetto [V. 1 & 2 parts]
41 • Aria (Lascia ch'io pianga) from Rinaldo by Handel.
39 • Athalia
32 • Iste confessor
5 • Messiah
45 • Patriotic Chorus
5 • Sechs Fugen
34 • Te Deum
31 • Te Deum [Laudamus] in Score Composed for His Grace the Duke of Chandos in the Year 1720 by G. F. Handel. No. 20.
Hansen, E. R.
39 • When shall we meet again - A sacred hymn
Harwood
39 • Funeral Anthem
Hässler, Johann Wilhelm
7 • Caprice et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Pianoforte par Jean Guillaume Haesler. Oeuv. V
7 • Fantaisie et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Forte-Piano par Jean Guillaume Haessler. Oeuvre III
7 • Fantaisie et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Forte-Piano par Jean Guillaume Haessler. Oeuvre IIII
7 • Prelude et Sonate pour le Clavecin ou Forte Piano par J. G. Haesler. Oeuvre VI
Hauf, F.
16 • Sonata
Häuser, Johann Ernst
7 • Terpsichore oder Museum der neuesten Modetänze. Eine musicalische Zeitschrift für mittlere Pianofortespieler,herausgegeben von J. E. Häuser. Zweiter Jahrgang in 6 Heften
Haydn, Franz Joseph
5 • Adagio für die Orgel
36 • Creation
36 • Die Worte des Erlösers am Kreuze, in Musik gesezt von Joseph Haydn. In Partitur.
24 • Haydn's Mass No. 4. Novello's edition.
26 • Mass in B-flat, No. 1
26 • Mass in C, No. 2
26 • Mass in C, No. 2. Organ accompaniment by W. A. Newland
26 • Mass in D, No. 3. Organ accompaniment by W. A. Newland
26 • Mass No. 4. Organ accompaniment by W. A. Newland, 1854
• O Jesu Deus. => see: Haydn, Mass in B-flat, Box 26
1-2 • Oeuvres Complette de Joseph Haydn. Cahier I-IV.
37 • Seven Last Words
37 • Seven Last Words; Introduzione
17 • Sonate pour le Piano-Forte accompagnée d'une Flute obligée composée par J. Haydn. Oeuvre 102, Liv. I.
• Te Deum. => see: Haydn, Mass in D, No. 3, Box 26
36 • The Creation, an Oratorio composed by Joseph Haydn.Arranged for the Organ or Piano Forte by Muzio Clementi.Improved from the first American Editionwith Verbal Emendations from the latest London Edition.
37 • The Seasons
Haydn, Michael
26 • Missa Solemnis in C
Henrion, Paul
44 • La Treille du roi. Opéra-comique en un acte. Paroles de M. Charles Depeuty.
Hérold, Louis Joseph Ferdinand
11 • Overture to Zampa by Herold.
21 • Zampa. Ouverture.
Herz, Henri
7 • Grande Fantaisie Brillante pour le Piano, sur un motif favori de l'Opéra d'Ambroise Thomas: La Double Échelle, par Henri Herz. Op. 98
Herz, Henri and Charles-Philippe Lafont
15 • Dernier Grand Duo par H. Herz et Lafont. Op. 110.
Heuberer, Charles F.
24 • Festival Mass for Four Voices and Organ Accompaniment. Composed by Charles F. Heuberer.
26 • Mass [in G]
Hiller, Friedrich Adam
45 • Hymne an die Tonkunst
Himmel, Friedrich Heinrich
44 • Fanchon das Leyermädchen, nach dem französischen Vaudeville bearbeitet von A. v. Kotzebue, in Musik gesetzt von Friederich Heinrich Himmel. Clavier Auszug.
Hoffmann, H. A.
42 • Air
Hoffmeister, Franz Anton
18 • IV Trios Concertants pour Deux Violon et Basse Composés par M. Hoffmeister. Oeuvre 13m.
Holloway, John T. (arranger)
47 • Singing School Exercises; designed to assist the teacher and aid pupils in singing schools in acquiring a practical knowledge of the principles of vocal music. Arranged by John T. Hollaway.
Hook, James
41 • For none but thee I'll marry. Sung by Mrs. Kennedy at Vauxhall. Set by Mr. Hook.
Horn, Henry
47 • Rudiments for the single and double movement harp. Exemplified in a clear & concise manner with forty-two exercises for forming the hands and the fingering marked (to which are subjoined) forty-two progressive lessons constructed on pleasing familiar airs arranged in the principle keys, with the fingering marked where necessary, by Henry Horn.
Hummel, Johann Nepomuk
8 • Grande Sonate pour Pianoforte par J. N. Hummel. Op. 20
8 • La bella Capricciosa pour le Pianoforte composée par J. N. Hummel
• March Jubilato. => see: Mozart, Mass No. 12, Box 28
• March Romain. => see: Mozart, Mass No. 12, Box 28
27 • Messe Solenne in E-flat
8 • Neue Wiener Walzer für's Forte-Piano in Musik Gesetzt von J. N. Hummel
8 • Rondeau pour le Piano Forté par Jean Nep. Hummel de Vienne
18 • Six grandes symphonies de W. A. Mozart arrangées pour le Piano Forte avec accompagnement de Flûte, Violon et Violoncelle par J. N. Hummel. No. 5.
8 • Souvenirs de Paganini Fantaisie pour le Piano-Forte par J. N. Hummel
8 • Trois Airs Anglais Variés pour le Piano-Forte par J. N. Hummel. Oeuvre 120. No.1 - The Ploughboy
Hünten, Franz
15 • Duo Concertant pour Piano & Violin, composé par François Hünten. Oeuvre 23.
Jackson, William
39 • Anthem - Turn ye to me
54 • Blow Ye the Trumpet on Zion
Jaspers, G.
15 • Sonatine pour le Clavecin ou Piano Forte Accompagnée d'un Violon par G. Jaspers. Oeuvre III.
Johnson, Ben
44 • Drink to me only. A favorite Glee for three Voices with the Original Words by Ben Johnson.
Jommelli, N.
54 • Glory Be to God on High: Chorus & Fuga
Jones, Geo. F.
39 • Krug
Jordan, Rev. P.
30 • [Requiem Mass]
27 • Mass for Children; Kyrie
27 • Requiem
Kalliwoda, J. W.
• Mass [in A], op. 137. => see: Weber, Mass in G, Box 29
27 • Mass in A, op. 137
Kelly, Michael
11 • The Overture to the Opera of Blue Beard as Performed at the Theatre Royal Drury Lane. Arranged for the Piano Forte by J. F. Bohlius.
Kirmair, Frederick Joseph
8 • Deux Airs Favoris, variés pour Piano-Forté par Kirmair. No. 100 du journal de musique pour les Dames. Seconde édition
Kleeberg, Christian Theophilus
8 • Vermischte Tänze für das Clavier oder Forte-Piano componirt von Kleeberg. Erste Sammlung
Kluge (arranger)
13 • Des Walses et Eccoisaises Favorite